- The whole point of Rocket Lab
is about democratising space,
and making space available for everybody.
It's an incredibly exciting
time in space right now.
We're right on that tipping point
of space being a
commercially-dominated domain
rather than a government-dominated domain.
We started with a blank sheet of paper.
And we said,
we want a launch for under
$5 million every week.
That's a pretty absurd statement
in the aerospace industry.
When you consider the average cost
of a launch vehicle is about $180 million,
and America as a country
went to space around about 20 times.
But the whole point is,
that piece of paper,
those two requirements drove
everything that we did.
Whether it be launch sites or engineering
or design and development.
We really took a very different approach,
we invested in lots of
emerging technologies.
When we started 3D
printing rocket engines,
we could see that technology
was going to play a very disruptive role
in trying to achieve what
we wanted to achieve.
And that can be said for
a number of the technologies
in the launch vehicle.
Rutherford is a very unique engine;
it's an electric turbo-pump cycle,
so it's like a hybrid of
a rocket and electronics.
We created that cycle
because it was the only cycle
that was going to meet our requirements
for launching weekly.
Normally you measure the time
to build a rocket engine in months.
We need to measure it in hours.
So with 3D printing,
we're able to print one
rocket engine every 24 hours.
And we've always,
we've been very clear
that we want to launch
at least once a week,
over 50 times a year.
Contrast that to America, as a country,
launching 20 times a year.
So if we're successful,
we'll be launching more as a
company than most countries.
All the launch sites in the
world are government-owned.
So we created the only and the first
fully-private orbital launch site.
I think if you wrote down everything
on the piece of paper that you had to do
bilateral treaties, space
agencies, legislation,
building launch vehicles, launch site,
it looks a little bit scary.
From my perspective,
New Zealand's a fantastic place
for really really high tech.
Especially where there's
a regulatory element,
because I think one of New
Zealand's unique propositions
is the tricky regulatory stuff
can be dealt with very pragmatically.
It's a very straightforward
and very transparent
and innovative place to do business.
To go to space and to
consistently go to space,
you need a certain level of
infrastructure and governance,
and quite frankly just
sheer capital intelligence.
I think that's a real
strength of New Zealanders.
For us it's not so much the technologies
that have been developed in New Zealand,
but more so the very very
clever and educated people
with the New Zealand attitude
of happy to push the boundaries.
Space is one of those things
that automatically defines
what level your country is operating at.
At the very peak of engineering.
And that's kind of the reality.
We expect to see quite an
influx of space companies
coming down to New Zealand.
(upbeat instrumental music)