(traditional flute music)
- Our ancestors were amongst the greatest
designers, engineers,
astrologers, scientists.
They got here before Captain Cook.
They sailed a third of
the planet to get here.
In waka that they had designed
that carried a hundred people.
I carry the Maori world view
which is one that says the footprints
that brought you to where you stand today
always lie in front of you.
It's your past that lies in front of you.
The technology that's allowed us
to go to the world is the internet.
I had decided we were
starting this business
and we're going to do it in Dunedin.
We would take on the world from Dunedin.
There's a lovely saying: ta tunga titi.
It's about the muttonbird.
The muttonbird is a bird
that flies the world
looking for opportunities.
Which it always brings home.
We used to say you gotta
think outside the box.
Technology has blown the box away.
We've worked with one of the
leading Formula One teams
and built the simulator that they use
for training their drivers.
We've never built one.
We just did something at the Masters,
at the golf.
I heard one of the people for CBS saying
to somebody they brought into the room.
We brought these Kiwis
up here because we knew
they would make it happen.
It really does come back to story.
I'd like to think that
that's the Maori part of me.
That technology has only ever been
a means to tell a story.
We took people out to see what sailors did
because they were at the peaks.
So let's have people understand the story
and in golf we're using technology
to show exactly why these
people are the best.
Why they deserve us watching them.
And if I think about Formula One
one of the fabulous stories we were able
to start telling there was this
is how good these guys are.
We really like to solve
problems that we think
are interesting and are gonna be fun.
The two things at our
core we like each other
we think the idea is really good
and that is how you put the deal together.
It's a different way of thinking.
The people we work with,
they're not a client,
they're part of the family;
don't let them down.
But actually as you look
back at relationships
you see how you got to where you are.
It doesn't mean your future's at your back
it means you walk forward
seeing that past all the time.
(traditional flute music)