Hello
I am a subtitle
Nothing to do with what this guy is saying
But I'm much more interesting than him.
[ROCKET LABS]
Believe me
My sheet of paper had a lot of cool drawings.
Much better than his paper.
I launched for five dollars.
Absurd indeed.
Why don't you just make some wings and fly to space?
blargh
Lalala I am a subtitle on multiple lines
isn't that interesting?
Goodbye
I'm leaving now.
Just kidding, lol.
You were fooled, weren't you?
I love the smell of napalm in the morning.
Do you feel lucky, punk?
Well, do ya?
This guy really talks a lot.
Talking about rocket hybrids...
I wonder...
It is as fuel-efficient as a Prius?
I'm getting bored of this
Help me, I'm trapped in this video!
How did I get in here?
There are rockets in here
Maybe I can shoot one at the screen.
...
How would you steal a rocket?
Easy, I've played enough GTA to steal a rocket
Alright, goodbye for real.
See you on the other side.